<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="mcgee_09_29_25-relax_NG_3.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<recipe>
    <instructions>
        <step num="1"> Preheat oven to 375° F.</step>
        <step num="2"> Combine flour, baking soda and salt in small bowl. Beat butter, granulated
            sugar, brown sugar and vanilla extract in large mixer bowl until creamy. Add eggs, one
            at a time, beating well after each addition. Gradually beat in flour mixture. Stir in
            morsels and nuts. Drop by rounded tablespoon onto ungreased baking sheets.</step>
        <step num="3"> Bake for 9 to 11 minutes or until golden brown. Cool on baking sheets for 2
            minutes; remove to wire racks to cool completely.</step>
        <variations>
            <alternative_cookie num="1">Pan Cookie Variation: Preheat oven to 350° F. Grease 15 x
                10-inch jelly-roll pan. Prepare dough as above. Spread into prepared pan. Bake for
                20 to 25 minutes or until golden brown. Cool in pan on wire rack. Makes 4 dozen
                bars.</alternative_cookie>
            <alternative_cookie num="2">Slice and Bake Cookie Variation: Prepare dough as above.
                Divide in half; wrap in waxed paper. Refrigerate for 1 hour or until firm. Shape
                each half into 15-inch log; wrap in wax paper. Refrigerate for 30 minutes.* Preheat
                oven to 375° F. Cut into 1/2-inch-thick slices; place on ungreased baking sheets.
                Bake for 8 to 10 minutes or until golden brown. Cool on baking sheets for 2 minutes;
                remove to wire racks to cool completely. Makes about 5 dozen cookies. * May be
                stored in refrigerator for up to 1 week or in freezer for up to 8
                weeks.</alternative_cookie>
        </variations>
        <note region="important">High Altitude Baking (5,200 feet): Increase flour to 2 1/2 cups.
            Add 2 teaspoons water with flour and reduce both granulated sugar and brown sugar to 2/3
            cup each. Bake drop cookies for 8 to 10 minutes and pan cookie for 17 to 19
            minutes.</note>
    </instructions>
    <ingredients>
        <ing>2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour</ing>
        <ing>1 teaspoon baking soda</ing>
        <ing>1 teaspoon salt</ing>
        <ing>1 cup (2 sticks) butter, softened</ing>
        <ing>3/4 cup granulated sugar</ing>
        <ing>3/4 cup packed brown sugar</ing>
        <ing>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</ing>
        <ing>2 large eggs</ing>
        <ing>2 cups (12-ounce package) NESTLÉ® TOLL HOUSE® Semi-Sweet Chocolate Morsels</ing>
        <ing optional="true">1 cup chopped nuts (Optional. If omitting, add 1 to 2 Tbsp. of
            all-purpose flour.)</ing>
    </ingredients>
</recipe>
